Robotics Researcher Yeshasvi Tirupad

□ (+39) 328-642-2578 | yeshasvitvs@gmail.com | yeshasvi.yeshi | # 02 August 1990 "Start where you are. Use what you have. Do what you can."



About_____

Robotics researcher primarily focused on enabling technologies for physical human-robot collaboration. Strong theoretical background in robot kinematics, dynamics and control, and thorough practical experience with robots of different complexity ranging from manipulators to humanoids. Experienced in system integration of complex software and hardware systems.

Experience ____

2020 - Present **Postdoctoral Fellow**

Dynamic Interaction Control IIT, Italy

• Developer - iFeelYou Bracelet COVID19 social distancing team

Early Stage Researcher & Doctoral Fellow

Dynamic Interaction Control

• Core Developer and Maintainer - Human Dynamics Estimation v2.0 Library

- Experience in Humanoid Whole-Body Control
- · Competence in Robot Simulation
- Open Source Contributor YARP, iDynTree, GazeboYarpPlugins, Wearables
- Seasoned in Agile Software Development & Research Methodologies
- Engaged in European Research Projects An.Dy, PACE
- Facilitated Technology Transfer

Master Thesis Mar - Sep 2015

Event-Driven Perception for Robotics

IIT, Italy

2016 - 2020

· Bio-inspired optical flow estimation and vergence control with neuromorphic stereo vision system on iCub [C7]

Graduate Research Jan - Mar 2015

FMARO Lab Genova University, Italy

- Gesture recognition through wearable sensors for human-robot interaction [W6]
- · AND-OR graph library for task planning during human-robot collaboration

Teaching Assistant Jul - Sep 2014

EMARO Lab

Genova University, Italy

• Developer of Pan-Tilt setup for teaching Software Architecture using ROS

Automation Engineer 2011 - 2013

Madras Rubber Factory Ltd.

Pondicherry, India

• Commissioning and Maintenance of Tyre Manufacturing Machines

Doctoral Research __

My doctoral research is aimed at addressing some of the research challenges to enabling human-robot collaboration. In particular, I worked on a holistic human perception framework for real-time monitoring of whole-body human motion and dynamics, to communicate human partner's intentions and needs in real-time to a robot partner for successful realization of a collaborative task [W2, C2, C1, U1]. Furthermore, I worked on the challenge of leveraging assistance from a human partner to improve human-robot collaboration. In this direction, an attempt at methodically defining what constitutes an assistance from a human partner is investigated and proposed partner-aware robot control strategies to endow robots with the capacity to meaningfully engage in a collaborative task [C3, C4, C6].

Education_

PhD, Human-Robot Collaboration

Italian Institute of Technology (IIT)

2016 - 2020 Genova, Italy

MSc, Advanced Robotics

2014 - 2015

University of Genova

Genova, Italy

MSc, Robotics Engineering

2013 - 2014

École Centrale de Nantes

Nantes, France

BTech, Electrical Engineering

2007 - 2011

Pondicherry University

Pondicherry, India

References _____

Dr. Daniele Pucci

Researcher

daniele.pucci@iit.it IIT, Italy

117

Dr. Silvio Traversaro

Researcher

silvio.traversaro@iit.it

Dr. Chiara Bartolozzi

Researcher

chiara.bartolozzi@iit.it

Dr. Fulvio Mastrogiovanni

Professor

fulvio.mastrogiovanni@unige.it

Genova University

Scholarships & Awards ____

Best Student Paper Award [C3]

2019

Intelligent Systems Conference

Best Blooper Award

2019

Early Stage Researcher

2016

Marie Skłodowska-Curie Fellowship

European Union

Technical Skills _____

Robotics Middleware

ROS, YARP

Operating Systems

Linux

Version Control Git, GitHub, Bitbucket **Programming** C++, Matlab, Python

Simulation

Gazebo

Qt, Eclipse, PyCharm

Simulink

Personal Skills

Resourceful Collaborative Dependable

Languages & Hobbies _____

English (C2) Italian (A2) French (A1) Hindi (B1) Tamil (B1) Telugu (C2) Hiking Photography Cooking

Publications_

- [C1] I. Sorrentino, F. J. Andrade Chavez, C. Latella, L. Fiorio, S. Traversaro, L. Rapetti, **Y. Tirupachuri**, N. Guedelha, M. Maggiali, S. Dussoni, G. Metta, and D. Pucci. "A Novel Sensorised Insole for Sensing Feet Pressure Distributions". In: *Sensors* 20.3 (2020). ISSN: 1424-8220. DOI: 10.3390/s20030747. URL: https://www.mdpi.com/1424-8220/20/3/747.
- [C2] C. Latella, S. Traversaro, D. Ferigo, **Y. Tirupachuri**, L. Rapetti, F. J. Andrade Chavez, F. Nori, and D. Pucci. "Simultaneous Floating-Base Estimation of Human Kinematics and Joint Torques". In: *Sensors* 19.12 (2019). ISSN: 1424-8220. DOI: 10.3390/s19122794. URL: https://www.mdpi.com/1424-8220/19/12/2794.
- [C3] **Y. Tirupachuri**, G. Nava, C. Latella, D. Ferigo, L. Rapetti, L. Tagliapietra, F. Nori, and D. Pucci. "Towards Partner-Aware Humanoid Robot Control Under Physical Interactions". In: *Proceedings of SAI Intelligent Systems Conference*. Springer. 2019, pp. 1073–1092.
- [C4] **Y. Tirupachuri**, G. Nava, L. Rapetti, C. Latella, and D. Pucci. "Trajectory Advancement during Human-Robot Collaboration". In: 2019 28th IEEE International Conference on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO-MAN). IEEE. 2019, pp. 1–8. DOI: 10.1109/RO-MAN46459.2019.8956339.
- [C5] **Y. Tirupachuri**, S. Traversaro, F. Nori, and D. Pucci. "Momentum-Based Topology Estimation of Articulated Objects". In: *Proceedings of SAI Intelligent Systems Conference*. Springer. 2019, pp. 1093–1105.
- [C6] **Y. Tirupachuri***, K. Darvish*, G. Romualdi, L. Rapetti, D. Ferigo, F. J. Andrade Chavez, and D. Pucci. "Whole-Body Geometric Retargeting for Humanoid Robots". In: *Humanoids*. IEEE. 2019, in press.
- [C7] V. Vasco, A. Glover, **Y. Tirupachuri**, F. Solari, M. Chessa, and C. Bartolozzi. "Vergence control with a neuromorphic iCub". In: 2016 IEEE-RAS 16th International Conference on Humanoid Robots (Humanoids). 2016, pp. 732–738. DOI: 10.1109/HUMANOIDS. 2016.7803355.

Under Review

[U1] L. Rapetti, **Y. Tirupachuri**, K. Darvish, C. Latella, and D. Pucci. "Model-Based Real-Time Motion Tracking using Dynamical Inverse Kinematics". In: (2020). arXiv: 1909.07669.

Workshops_

- [W1] L. Rapetti, **Y. Tirupachuri**, A. Ranavolo, C. Latella, and D. Pucci. "Multi-Humanoid-Robot system: balancing and effort distribution during collaboration". In: (2020), Foundational Problems in Multi-Robot Coordination Under Uncertainty and Adversial Attacks, International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2020, Paris, France. arXiv: 2001.00411 [cs.R0]. URL: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bAerev1fong0ZU-JL93wZowrGgxoPfve/view.
- [W2] Y. Tirupachuri, G. Nava, L. Rapetti, C. Latella, K. Darvish, and D. Pucci. "Recent Advances in Human-Robot Collaboration Towards Joint Action". In: (2020), The Communication Challenges in Joint Action for Human-Robot Interaction Workshop, International Conference on Social Robotics (ICSR) 2019, Madrid, Spain. arXiv: 2001.00411 [cs.R0].
- [W3] C. Latella, **Y. Tirupachuri**, L. Rapetti, D. Ferigo, S. Traversaro, I. Sorrentino, F. J. Andrade Chavez, F. Nori, and D. Pucci. "A Human Wearable Framework for Physical Human-Robot Interaction". In: (2019), I–RIM, Rome, Italy. URL: https://bit.ly/35iy9k7.
- [W4] **Y. Tirupachuri**, G. Nava, L. Rapetti, C. Latella, and D. Pucci. "Trajectory Advancement for Robot Stand-up with Human Assistance". In: (2019), I–RIM, Rome, Italy. arXiv: 1910.06786 [cs.RO].
- [W5] C. Latella, L. Tagliapietra, D. Ferigo, **Y. Tirupachuri**, F. Nori, and D. Pucci. "Advancing Human-Robot Collaboration through Online Human Inverse Dynamics Estimation". In: *2018 IEEE Workshop on Advanced Robotics and its Social Impacts (ARSO)*. 2018, pp. 21–22. DOI: 10.1109/ARSO.2018.8625806.
- [W6] Y. Tirupachuri, P. Ramadoss, B. Bruno, and F. Mastrogiovanni. "Human-Robot Cooperation: is Wearable Sensing the Way to Go?" In: (2015), Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO–MAN), 2015 IEEE 24th IEEE International Symposium on. eprint: https://bit.ly/2Qmgi7W.